NOEL J. CRUZ

(843) 619-8402 | noeljcruz1@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/noeljcruz Portfolio: noeljcruz.com | GitHub: github.com/noeljcruz

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Management and a passion for effective teamwork and learning/implementing new software technologies. Highly adaptable, leveraging military experience and resourcefulness to overcome challenging technical problems and develop comprehensive applications.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-end Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, React, Redux **Back-end Technologies**: Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Docker

EXPERIENCE

Cloud Application Developer Student Microsoft Software and Systems Academy

2022 – Present

Remote

- 17-week program centered around C# and .NET framework development. Implemented objectoriented design to build and deploy full-stack applications for the Azure cloud environment.
- Incorporated T-SQL relational databases, ASP.NET MVC, and web technologies.

Assoc. Software Engineer L3Harris Technologies

2020 - 2022

Chantilly, VA

- Mission Planning Tool (MPT) Team Lead for the Space Mission Integration program.
- Led a team of four engineers to build a web-based user interface for the company's legacy MPT product. Managed sprint planning, tasking, and set objectives to develop new features.
- Created React components to render planning data and resource properties for space missions. Implemented Redux store to manage state and handle HTTP data responses from external APIs.
- Setup front-end routing to navigate smoothly across the application. Spearheaded the integration of additional projects, expanding the utility of MPT, utilizing Docker containers.

Lead Intelligence Analyst / Navigation Division Lead

2015 - 2020

U.S. Coast Guard

San Pedro, CA / Charleston, SC

- Active TS/SCI Security Clearance. Experienced in handling sensitive information/data.
- Supervised 15 analysts in information collection, data analysis, and reporting in support of maritime law enforcement. Coordinated with over 50 interagency partners.
- Provided executive-level briefs to the Sector Command, detailing smuggling trends, threats to the port infrastructure, and counterterrorism awareness, to drive operational planning.

INDEPENDENT PROJECT

Toby Management | github.com/noeljcruz/toby-mgmt| toby-mgmt.herokuapp.com

- Full Stack H.R. platform for businesses to manage employee information. Incorporates user login, authentication, sessions, file upload, and database management.
- Technologies: ReactJS, MySQL/Sequelize, Express.js, bcrypt, Passport, Amazon S3.

EDUCATION

Certificate – Full Stack Web Development: UCLA Extension, Los Angeles, CA 2019 **Bachelor of Science – Management: U.S. Coast Guard Academy**, New London, CT 2015